

Contact Information

Cellphone:

+55 (12) 98120-1460

fredpelogia@outlook.com fpelogia@unifesp.br

Linkedin:

www.linkedin.com/in/fpelogia

Portfolio (GitHub):

fpelogia.github.io

Address:

Av. Presidente Juscelino Kubitschek, 5490. Ap. 98 São José dos Campos - SP Brazil

Languages

Portuguese - Native English









Speaking

Skills

Programming Languages:

- Python
- Typescript
- C / C++
- Angular / NestJS
- NodeJS
- HTML, CSS, JS

Others

- Relational Database design and implementation (PostgreSQL, MySQL)
- ORM with Prisma ORM
- Deploy on Heroku / AWS Cloud
- Problem Solving / Modelling

Publications

Multi-wave modelling and short-term prediction of ICU bed occupancy by patients with Covid-19 in regions of Italy Mathematical Modelling of Natural Phenomena 19, 13 - (2024)

Short-term prediction of COVID-19 deaths in Argentina IFMBE (International Federation for Medical and Biological Engineering) Proceedings - CLAIB 2022

Study of the COVID-19 pandemic trending behavior in Israeli cities

IFAC Papers Online - 11th IFAC Symposium on Biological and Medical Systems BMS 2021

COVID-19 Trend Analysis in Mexican States and Cities 43rd Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine & Biology Society (EMBC) 2021

A support tool for planning classrooms considering social distancing between students

Computational and Applied Mathematics (2022)

Objectives

With a mixed background in research and corporate projects, I have been very interested in opportunities to apply computing and technology to solve problems in a wide variety of fields.

I have a special interest in Data Science, R&D, computational modelling & simulation

Experience



Embraer - Software Developer II - EVE

2021 - Now

- · Development of IT solutions for EVE Air Mobility's Support and Services
- Full Stack development of web applications Backend APIs (NodeJS/Python), Front-end (Angular), Database (PostgreSQL), Deploy with CI/CD Azure DevOps and AWS, Docker and K8S
- Collaborative planning of the data ecosystem and application architecture
- Working together with the business area (Reliability and Maintenance Costs), with active participation in solution planning
- Automating data collection and treatment processes (Python, VBA)
- Planning solutions and new projects in data science (NLP, SVM, OCR)

Embraer - IT Internship - Support & Services

- Support internal applications and APIs (Full-Stack JS / Node) for **Executive Aviation**
- Automating processes with Python



MSc. Research Project - Mathematical Modelling

2021 - 2024

- Mathematical and computational modeling of the evolution of COVID-19 indicators, performing short-term forecasts of ICU bed occupancy by patients with the disease
- Model developed and implemented in Python, using libraries such as SciPy, Numpy, Matplotlib,
- · Graphical interface to aid experimentation with the simulations using Streamlit (Python framework).



Undergraduate Research (FAPESP)

2019 - 2020

- "From scratch" implementation of deep neural networks using different optimization methods (GD, SGD, RMS Prop, Adam, Levenberg-Marquardt) applied to Fraud Detection.
- · Collaboration with researchers in applied mathematics



Other Projects

2020 - 2022

- Planned Room: Tool for planning classrooms considering social distancing between students - Optimization problem
 - Collaboration with researchers in the fields of applied mathematics and operations research
- SABER-SUS: Full Stack development of a web application for clinical practice guideline recommendations for the treatment of chronic diseases

Education



Federal University of São Paulo (UNIFESP)

2022 - 2024	Master's Degree in Biomedical Engineering
2018 - 2022	Computer Engineering
2018 - 2021	Interdisciplinary Bachelor in Science and Technology